Mss.B.W243 Mss.B.W243
American Philosophical Society
- Papers, 1850-1864
  - Letter to John Warner, March 1, 1858; 8" x 10"; Jeanes, Joseph
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to the distribution of his work.
  - Letter to John Warner, March 4, 1858; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Maule, Joseph E.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Writes on behalf of the overseers of the Monthly meeting of Friends of Philadelphia, of which Mr. Warner is a member, regarding his religious practices.
  - Letter to John Warner, March 5, 1858; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
  - Letter to Jos. E. Maule, March 8, 1858; 8" x 10"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 2p. States his religious principles upon the subject of a man made and a hireling ministry in contrast to the belief of the Society of Friends.
  - Letter to John Warner, March 19, 1858; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Disagrees with Newton's philosophy. Gives Warner scientific advice. Moves to West Newton in May.
  - Letter to John Warner, April 8, 1858; 5" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, A.L.S. 3p. Mentions the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, April 25, 1858; 7 3/4" x 10"; Warner, Joseph
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Desires information about property deeded to the Friends by Burd Pattison about 1830.
  - Letter to uncle [Joseph Warner], April 26, 1858; 8" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 1p. Replies to his letter relative to the meeting house property.
  - Letter to [John Warner], May 4, 1858; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Vaughan, Daniel, ca. 1821-1879
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 1p. Printed enc. - 2p. Acknowledges receipt of his work on organic morphology. Sends a circular containing an announcement of some new views [addressed to the members of the AAAS].
  - Letter to [John] Warner, May 10, 1858; 5" x 8"; Yardley, Thomas W., 1826-1900
    A.L.S. 2p. (Accompanied by copy - 2p.) A talk with a mutual friend about Warner's book on morphology has resulted in an invitation to prepare a paper to be read at the AAAS meeting in Springfield. Refers to Peirce- Warner controversy.
  - Letter to T. W. Yardley, May 13, 1858; 6 1/4" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A. Dr. of L.S. 3p. and end. Relative to the possibility of a position for Mr. Warner with the Coast Survey. The Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to [John Warner], May 14, 1858; 8" x 10"; Morris, Ellwood, 1813?-1872
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Comments upon Mr. Warner's works.
  - Letter to David A. Wells, May 27, 1858; 8" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks him for the notice of his Studies in organic morphology which appeared in the Annual of scientific discovery; lays claim to being a pioneer in morphological research in America.
  - Letter to John Warner, May 28, 1858; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy; mentions the American philosophical society.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 2, 1858; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Miskey, William F.
  - Letter to [T.W.] Yardley, June 3, [1858]; 5" x 7"; Foulke, William Parker
    Ms. note. 1p. Mutilated. Relative to the [Peirce]-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 3, 1858; 6 1/2" x 8"; Foulke, William Parker
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. (Accompanied by a 4p. copy of same) Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to W. Parker Foulke, June 6, 1858; 5" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 2p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy. Regrets his intentions with regard to the Coast survey have been interfered with.
  - Letter to W. Parker Foulke, June 6, 1858; 6 1/4" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A. copy of L.S. 2p. and end. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 7, 1858; 8" x 10 1/2"; Camden, R. L. M.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. Relative to the distribution of copies of Warner's Organic Morphology; and the controversy with Prof. Peirce.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 7, 1858; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, June 7, 1858; 7 3/4" x 10"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 1p. and end. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, June 9, 1858; 8" x 10"; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Advice relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy. Mentions C[hauncey] Wright and [ ] LeConte.
  - Letter to W. F. Miskey, June 9, 1858; 8" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L. 1p. and enc. - 2p. and end. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy; encloses a few hints which might be used by the Ledger.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 10, 1858; 8" x 10"; Jeanes, Joseph
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Comments on the [Peirce]-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to W.F. Miskey, June 14, 1858; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 1p. Inquires whether he received his letter of the 9th.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 15, 1858; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Warner, June 20, 1858; 8" x 10"; Royal Society (Great Britain)
    Printed L.S.: W. H. Miller, foreign secretary 1p. and add. Acknowledges receipt of his Studies in organic morphology.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, June 22, 1858; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L.S. 8p. Comments upon scientists of the period; the Peirce-Winslow controversy. His ideas on cosmography.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 25, [1858?]; 5" x 8"; Wells, David Ames, 1828-1898
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Advice with regard to the publication of his book. Comments upon the Albany observatory controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 26, 1858; 8" x 10"; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. (Accompanied by a copy - 4p.) Advice relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy; mentions the LeConte article.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, June 26, 1858; 6 1/4" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 3p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, July 6, 1858; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
  - Letter to [John Warner], July 7, 1858; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L. 6p. Comments upon scientists of the day; the Cambridge professors. His scientific doctrines.
  - Letter to [John Warner], July 10, 1858; 5" x 8"; Spackman, J. B.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Orders copies of his work on morphology.
  - Letter to John Warner, July 17, 1858; 5" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 4p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy
  - Letter to John Warner, July 20, 1858; 5" x 8"; Foulke, William Parker
    Haddonfield, N.J., A.L.S. 2p. Relative to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to [John Warner], July 20, 1858; 5" x 8"; Spackman, J. B.
  - Letter to John Warner, July 22, 1858; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
  - Letter to John Warner, July 23, 1858; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
  - Letter to John Warner, July 27, 1858; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
  - Letter to [John Warner], Aug. 1, 1858; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L.S. 4p. The Peirce-Warner controversy. Comments upon scientists of the day.
  - Letter to John Warner, Sept. 10, 1858; 5" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, A.L.S. 3p. Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, Sept. 11, 1858; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L.S. 4p. The Dudley observatory controversy. The Cambridge professors.
  - Letter to C.F. Winslow, Sept. 16, 1858; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L. 2p. The Dudley observatory controversy; his own controversy with Prof. Peirce.
  - Letter to John Warner, Sept. 30, 1858; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L.S. 6p. The Dudley observatory controversy. Would like to see Mr. Warner in some good mathematical position.
  - Letter to John Warner, Oct. 2, 1858; 5" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 2p. Relative to the Dudley observatory controversy.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Oct. 31, 1858; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L.S. 2p. The Dudley observatory. Peirce.
  - Letter to [John Warner], Nov. 29, 1858; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L.S. 4p. His son. The Coast survey. Peirce.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Dec. 8, 1858; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Dorsey, George W., 1827-1909
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to the sale of a house.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 9, 1858; 5" x 6 3/4"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 3p. Mentions several scientists of the day.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 20, 1858; 5" x 8"; Morris, Ellwood, 1813?-1872
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. Peirce-Warner controversy. Use of locomotives in coal mines.
  - Letter to ---- ----, 1858-1859; 8" x 10"; Warner, John, -1873
    [ca.] A.L.S. with initials. 1p. (Only last page) The Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to P.W. Sheafer, Feb. 8(?), 1859; 8" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Woodside, A. copy of L.S. 1p. Encloses sketch showing where the gangway of the Forestville colliery crossed the east and north lines of the Bluw (?) Tract in 1856.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov.12, 1859; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Mackey, M. S.
    Muncy, A(?)L.S. 2p. Relative to a note which is due.
  - Letter to John Warner, Jan. 5, 1859; 5 1/4" x 8"; Camden, R. L. M.
    Paris, A.L.S. 8p. Warner's Organic Morphology; suggests publishing it in French for European circulation. Comments upon the Peirce controversy.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Jan. 9, 1859; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L.S. 4p. Goes to Detroit to deliver his lecture on "Geology and the deluge." Questions possibility of giving it in other cities. The Dudley observatory controversy.
  - Letter to [John Warner], Jan. 26, 1859; 8" x 10"; Wells, David Ames, 1828-1898
    Troy, N.Y., [ca.]. A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John Warner, Jan. 29, 1859; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Dorsey, George W., 1827-1909
  - Letter to John Warner, Jan. 31, 1859; 5" x 8"; Sheafer, P. W. (Peter Wenrick), b. 1819
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledge receipt of the report of the survey of mines near the northwest corner of Phoenixville. Mentions the Pottsville scientific association.
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 7, 1859; 5" x 8"; Sheafer, P. W. (Peter Wenrick), b. 1819
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to a possible survey of the Phoenix lines.
  - Letter to Joh Warner, Feb. 10, 1859; 8 1/2" x 11"; Vienna. K. akademie der wissenschaften.
    Wien, Printed L.S: D. H(?) Schnatt---, general secretär. 1p. Acknowledges receipt of his Studies in organic morphology.
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 14, 1859; 5 3/4" x 9 1/2"; K. sächsische gesellschaft der wissenschaften, Leipzig
    Leipzig, Printed L.S: E. H. Weber, secretär. 1p. In German. Acknowledges receipt of his Studies in organic morphology.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Feb. 26, [1859]; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L.S. 6p. His present interest in a young seaman who is charged with murder. His philosophy
  - Letter to John Warner, March 7, 1859; 4 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Wells, David Ames, 1828-1898
    Troy, A.L.S. 3p. Acknowledges his paper on earthwork which will appear in his Annual [of scientific discovery. Asks for a recommendation of his series of scientific school books. Refers to the Peirce-Warner controversy.
  - Letter to John Warner, March 20, 1859; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Dorsey, George W., 1827-1909
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to the sale of his house.
  - Letter to John Warner, March 22, 1859; 5" x 8"; Wells, David Ames, 1828-1898
    Troy, N.Y., A.L.S. 4p. Appreciates Mr. Warner's efforts in his behalf. Sends a package of his books. Comments on scientists of the day.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, March 28, 1859; 5 1/4" x 8"; Gillespie, W. M. (William Mitchell), 1816-1868
    Schenectady, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Desires copy of Mr. Warner's work on earthwork.
  - Letter to John Warner, April 5, [1859]; 5" x 8"; Wells, David Ames, 1828-1898
    Troy, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p. Sends 12 sets of his books and a set of Gray's botanies.
  - Letter to W.M. Gillespie, April 6, 1859; 7 1/2" x 10"; Warner, John, -1873
    Woodside, Pa., A. copy of L.S. 2p. and end. His work on earthwork now in the hands of a Philadelphia publisher. Is engaged in land and mine surveying.
  - Letter to John Warner, April 20, 1859; 8" x 10 1/2"; Camden, R. L. M.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Acknowledges material on the Dudley observatory difficulty which he supposes came from Mr. Warner.
  - Letter to John Warner, April 20, 1859; 5" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, A.L.S. 3p. Comments on scientists and their works.
  - Letter to John Warner, May 22, 1859; 5" x 8"; Wells, David Ames, 1828-1898
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Suggestions regarding the publication of Mr. Warner's Tables.
  - Letter to John Warner, May 27, 1859; 5" x 8"; Stokes, Joseph (?)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Asks for correct address so that he may send the Book of Advices of the Society of Friends.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, May 28, 1859; 8" x 10"; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    A.L.S. 1p. Assures him that nothing will cool their friendship.
  - Letter to brother [John Warner], May 30, 1859; 6 1/2" x 8"; Warner, Sally
    Redwood farm, A.L.S. 2p. Family letter.
  - Letter to Jos. W. Stokes, June 1, 1859; 9 1/2" x 13"; Warner, John, -1873
    Woodside, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Probably a letterpress copy. Will be pleased to receive the Book of Advices.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 6, 1859; 5" x 8"; Jones, N. F.
    Smethport, A.L.S. 1p. Relative to the publication of Warner's Tables.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 13, 1859; 8" x 8 1/2"; Mackey, M. S.
    Muncy, A.L.S. 1P. Relative to the purchase of the steam engine which Mr. Warner has for sale.
  - Letter to M.S. Mackey, June 15, 1859; 9 1/2" x 13"; Warner, John, -1873
    Woodside, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Probably a letterpress copy. Relative to the sale of an engine.
  - Letter to John Warner, July 11, 1859; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Gillespie, W. M. (William Mitchell), 1816-1868
    Schenectady, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Enters subscription for Mr. Warner's work on earthwork.
  - Letter to W. M. Gillespie, July 16, 1859; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Warner, John, -1873
    Woodside, Pa., A.Dr. of L.S. 3p. Relative to the publication of his Tables.
  - Letter to John Warner, July 19, 1859; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Relates to a work by Mr. Warner being published by Lippincott & co.
  - Letter to Joseph Henry, July 25, 1859; 7 3/4" x 10"; Warner, John, -1873
    Pottsville, A.Dr. of L.S. 1p. Acknowledges a certain circular from the [smithsonian] institution.
  - Letter to John Warner, Aug. 17, 1859; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L.S. 6p. Account of his efforts which saved Plumer (?) from the scaffold. Peirce.
  - Letter to John Warner, Aug. 20, 1859; 8" x 10"; Morris, Ellwood, 1813?-1872
    Averysborough N.C., A.L.S. 1p. Mr. Warner's Tables of earthwork.
  - Letter to W.M. Gillespie, Aug. 22, 1859; 7 1/2" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Woodside, A.Dr. of L.S. 2p. (Accompanied by another copy with a few additional notes) Relative to his Tables.
  - Letter to John Warner, Sept. 10, 1859; 8" x 10"; Morris, Ellwood, 1813?-1872
    Averysborough, N.C., A.L.S. 2p. Suggests that Mr. Warner try to interest B.H. Latrobe, the ablest living railroad engineer, in his recent work on earthwork.
  - Letter to John Warner, Sept. 13, 1859; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles W.
    West Newton, A.L.S. 3p. Is now at home looking for another position.
  - Letter to John Warner, Sept. 15, 1859; 8" x 10"; Morris, Ellwood, 1813?-1872
    Averysborough, A.L.S. 2p. Did his best to advance the interests of Schuylkill county by the promotion of the Allentown line.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Aug. 27, [1859]; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L.S. 3p. Mr. Warner's new book.
  - Letter to W.M. Gillespie, Oct. 14, 1859; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Warner, John, -1873
    Woodside, Pa., A.Dr. of L.S. 2p. Relative to his Tables.
  - Letter to John Warner, Oct. 27, 1859; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    West Newton, A.L.S. 3p. Sympathy on death of his uncle. Is deliberating on the idea of going to South America.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov. 3, 1859; 8" x 10 1/2"; Camden, R. L. M.
    Paris, A.L.S. 7p. Additional comments upon [Benjamin] Peirce. Dissensions among scientists.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov. 10, 1859; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    A.L.S. 6p. Philosophy of life. Mentions [John] Brown.
  - Letter to brother [John Warner], Nov. 11, 1859; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Warner, Redwood Fisher, b. 1818
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Relative to the executorship of their uncle's estate.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 7, 1859; 5" x 8"; Lippincott, J. B. & Co.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S: W.S. Washburn. Send proofs of his "Tables."
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 14, 1859; 5" x 8"; Wells, David Ames, 1828-1898
    Troy, A.L.S. 3p. Is busy with the publication of his Annual and text books; offers to publish any material for Mr. Warner.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 24, 1859; 5" x 8"; Lippincott, J. B. & Co.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S: W. S. Washburn. 1p. Relative to his "Tables."
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Jan. 8, 1860; 8" x 10"; Jones, N. F.
    Cape Fear River, N.C., A.L.S. 3p. Comments on negroes and the political situation of the South. publication of Warner's Tables.
  - Letter to D.A. Wells, Jan. 9, 1860; 8" x 10"; Miskey, William F.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Will attempt to procure a copy of Rodger's Geology.
  - Letter to W.F. Miskey, Jan. 31, 1860; 8" x 9 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Woodside, A.L.S. 1p. Letterpress (?) D.A. Wells is willing to go as high as $25 for a copy of Roger's Report.
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 1, 1860; 8" x 5 3/4"; Maingay (?), Robert A.
    Minersville, A.L.S. 1p. In pencil. Desires to borrow a book on perspective.
  - Letter to R.A. Maingay (?), Feb. 2, 1860; 9" x 12"; Warner, John, -1873
    Woodside, A.L.S. 1p. Letterpress. Mutilated and faded. Books on industrial drawing borrowed from Geo. K. Smith.
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 3, 1860; 5" x 8"; Lippincott, J. B. & Co.
  - Letter to W.M. Gillespie, Feb. 9, 1860; 5" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Woodside, Pa., A.Dr. of L.S. 3p. Encloses sample of his Tables, the printing of which is delayed for want of time to read proof.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Feb. 15, 1860; 5" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to John Warner, Feb. 19, 1860; 5" x 8"; Loeser, C. (Christopher)
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 2p. (Contains also a letter from Red to his brother, John Warner, Feb. 21, 1860)
  - Letter to brother [John Warner], Feb. 21, 1860; Warner, Redwood Fisher, b. 1818
    A.L.S. 1p. (on same sheet with letter from C. Loeser to J. Warner, Feb. 19,1860)
  - Letter to John Warner, May 10, 1860; 8" x 10"; Morris, Ellwood, 1813?-1872
    Buckhorn (?) canal, N.C., A.L.S. 1p. Is glad to hear of Warner's resolution to complete his Tables and book.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 19, 1860; 8" x 10"; Morris, Ellwood, 1813?-1872
    Averysborough, N.C., A.L.S. 3p. Suggestions with regard to Mr. Warner's mathematical works.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, June 21, 1860; 5" x 8"; Jones, N. F.
    Smethport, A.L.S. 4p. Warner's Tables. His work.
  - Letter to John Warner, July 7, 1860; 8" x 10"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Boston, A.L.S. 5p. Glad that his new independence will allow him to cultivate his morphological pursuits. Winslow's studies relative to solar repulsion; Peirce's use of same.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, July 20, 1860; 8" x 10"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Boston, A.L.S. 3p. Encloses complimentary references of his work which Mr. Warner may use as he sees fit. Recommends Humboldt's letters.
  - Letter to John Warner, July 23, 1860; 8" x 10"; Morris, Ellwood, 1813?-1872
    Averysborough N.C., A.L.S. 1p. Suggestions relative to Mr. Warner's Tables.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Warner, Aug. 4, 1860; 5" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 2p. Indiana politics; thinks Lincoln will get the state's vote.
  - Letter to John Warner, Sept. 2, 1860; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Boston, A.L.S. 4p. Comments on Humboldt as a scientific scholar. Agassiz's new museum; Winslow's donation to it.
  - Letter to John Warner, Jan. 16, 1861; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Boston, A.L.S. 4p. Comments on Warner's present mathematical labors [Tables]. Comments on politics.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Feb. 14, 1861; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Jones, N. F.
    Comet Wells,Pa., A.L.S. 3p. Publication of Warner's Tables. Oil wells.
  - Letter to John Warner, May 4, 1861; 5" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington,Ind., A.L.S. 3p. Suggests the possibility of having an A.M. degree awarded to Mr. Warner by the University. Indiana's views on secession.
  - Letter to John Warner, May 21, 1861; 5" x 8"; Winslow, Charles Frederick, 1811-1877
    Boston, A.L.S. 6p. The South and the war. Comments on D.A. Wells' First principles of geology.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 14, 1861; 5" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 28, 1861; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Indiana University
    Bloomington, A.L.S.: Daniel Kirkwood, secretary of the faculty. 1p. Announcement that the University has conferred upon him the honorary degree of Master of Arts.
  - Letter to John Warner, June 29, 1861; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Indiana University
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S: Robert C. Foster, secy. Ind. unty. 1p. Seal. Announcement that he has been admitted to the degree of Master of Arts.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Warner, July 1, 1861; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, A.L.S. 1p. Comments on comet seen the night before.
  - Letter to John Warner, July 24, 1861; 8" x 10 1/2"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 2p. Suggests the possibility of having his mathematical papers published in the Mathematical monthly. Disappointed in the results of the battle of Manassas.
  - Letter to John Warner, Sept. 30, 1861; 5 1/2" x 9"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, A.L.S. 1p. Warner's paper on the hyperbola appears in the last Mathematical monthly.
  - Letter to John Warner, Nov. 14, 1861; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Jones, N. F.
    Comet Wells, A.L.S. 2p. Asks his aid in securing a position with the Philadelphia and Erie R.R.
  - Letter to W.M. Gillespie, Nov. 20, 1861; 5" x 8"; Warner, John, -1873
    Philadelphia, A. copy of L.S. 1p. Sends a copy of his book on earthwork.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Nov. 29, 1861; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Jones, N. F.
    Comet Wells, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to John Warner, Dec. 3, 1861; 5 1/4" x 8"; Gillespie, W. M. (William Mitchell), 1816-1868
    Schenectady, N.Y., A.L.S. 3p. Comments upon Mr. Warner's work on earthwork.
  - Letter to W.M. Gillespie, Dec. 26, 1861; 8" x 12 1/2"; Warner, John, -1873
    Bridgewater, Pa., A.Dr. of L. 4p. Thanks for his encouraging reception of his work [on earthwork]. Exchange of ideas on same.
  - Letter to John Warner, Jan. 2, 1862; 5" x 8"; Kirkwood, Daniel, 1814-1895
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 2p. Comments on Warner's book.
  - Letter to [John] Warner, Jan. 5, 1862; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Jones, N. F.
    Comet Wells, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to W. M. Gillespie, April 26, 1862; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Warner, John, -1873
    Philadelphia, A. copy of L.S. 1p. Will leave the question of equivalent level heights until Prof. Gillespie has examined his comments upon the subject.